# **Bernard Balansag**

Experienced Web and Mobile Developer with a demonstrated history of working in the information technology and services industry. with knowledge and experience with c#, php, JavaScript also in relational databases such as MySQL and MySQL and other related frameworks.

**EXPERIENCE** 

# INGRAM MICRO, - Professional, business systems (Web and Mobile Developer)

JANUARY 2023 - PRESENT (Hybrid)

Role:

 Full-stack web and mobile application development, including ongoing maintenance and support.

## King VA Services, - (Mobile developer)

FEBRUARY 2023 - DECEMBER 2023 (Remote)

Role

 Developed Android and iOS versions of a multimedia application for a U.S.-based client.

# Lily pad Digital Solutions, Remote - *Mobile Developer* NOVEMBER 2022 – JULY 2023 (Remote)

Role:

 Contributed to application development for Android platforms using Kotlin.

**SEIKO IT SOLUTION PHILIPPINES, INC., -** *Software Engineer* 2906 Antel Global Corporate Center, Ortigas Center, Pasig City.

AUGUST 2021 - DECEMBER 2022

Role:

 Develop and maintain new and existing projects for major clients, managing project timelines, resource allocation, and deliverables.
Lead teams through all phases of the development lifecycle, including requirements gathering, development, testing, deployment, and client support, both onsite and remotely.

WCube Solutions Inc, - Web Developer 408, West City Plaza, Mabuhay, 66 West Avenue, Lungsod Quezon, 1104 Kalakhang Maynila FEBRUARY 2021 – April 2021

Role:

 Deploy and manage Laravel website and provide technical support in systems update and fix. Blk. 23 lot 10, brgy. 180, miramonte park subdivision, purification street, caloocan city (+63) 9091067604 nhardbalansag@gmail.com

### **EDUCATION**

Polytechnic University of the Philippines, Main Campus Sta. Mesa Manila — Bachelor of Science in Information Technology

June 2017 - 2021

Manuel Luis Quezon High School, Camia Street Malaria Caloocan City — *High School* 

June 2010 - March 2014

#### **SKILLS**

#### Frameworks:

- Laravel
- React Native
- React JS
- C# .Net
- Node JS

### Programming:

- PHP
- JavaScript
- C#
- Java
- Scala
- IOT (Raspberry pie and Arduino)

## Frontend:

- HTML
- CSS
- JavaScript

#### Tools:

- Linux
- Postman
- Git Versioning Control (Bitbucket, Jira, GitHub)

#### Database:

- MYSQL
- MSSQL
- Firebase

### **EXPERIENCE**

Bentacos Corporation, 27, Annapolis Boutique Residences, Annapolis Street Greenhills, San Juan City 1502, Philippines — *Web and Mobile Developer Internship* 

OCTOBER 2020 - FEBRUARY 2021

Role:

 Develop Mobile Application and Web Application Systems for client needs and provide technical support for current projects.

# **BA Lepanto Condominium Corporation,** 8747, Paseo de Roxas Makati City — *Housekeeping*

February 2015 - October 2021

Role:

- Cleaning and maintaining the building. provide technical assistance and maintenance to the building computers, components and network connections
- Develop buildings E-Directory Software

### **LANGUAGE**

- English
- Filipino